Guide to the Student Papers reference collection, circa 1890-ongoing UA.01.11.0017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Student Papers reference collection
1890-1906, 1976-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0017
1 Linear Feet 2 boxes 28 items
The Student Papers Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. The collection consists primarily of Duke undergraduate student papers on topics concerning Duke University or Durham. The three earliest student papers date from circa 1890, 1895, and 1906, and were written by N. Raine Reed, Fannie W. Carr, and Raymond Browning, respectively. Paper topics present in the collection include: the founding of Duke; the undergraduate curriculum; Duke Chapel; 1969 Allen Building Takeover; Methodism and its relation to Duke University; the 1942 Rose Bowl; desegregation; and gender issues at Duke.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Student Papers Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Collection Overview
The Student Papers Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. The collection consists primarily of Duke undergraduate student papers on topics concerning Duke University or Durham. The three earliest student papers date from circa 1890, 1895, and 1906, and were written by N. Raine Reed, Fannie W. Carr, and Raymond Browning, respectively. Paper topics present in the collection include: the founding of Duke; the undergraduate curriculum; Duke Chapel; 1969 Allen Building Takeover; Methodism and its relation to Duke University; the 1942 Rose Bowl; desegregation; and gender issues at Duke.
Related Material
Dept. of Cultural Anthropology records, 1973-1992.
University Archives, Duke University.
Department of History Course Papers and Oral History Interviews, 1974.
University Archives, Duke University.
Dept. of History records, 1947-2000.
University Archives, Duke University.
Dept. of Public Policy records, 1971-[on-going].
University Archives, Duke University.
Mathematics Dept. Student Honors Papers, 1991-2005.
University Archives, Duke University.
Program in Education records, 1985-2000.
University Archives, Duke University.
University Writing Program records, 1997-2007.
University Archives, Duke University.
Academic writing; Report writing -- Study and teaching (Higher); English language -- Writing -- Study and teaching (Higher)
- Student Papers, 1890-
  - N. R[aine]. Reid
    - The Founder of Trinity College, circa 1890 (Box 1)
  - Fannie W. Carr
    - Relation of Christianity to the Social Problems, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Raymond Browning
    - After-Study Meditations, 1906 (Box 1)
  - Ann Robertson Britt papers
    - A Chronological Study of Undergraduate Curriculum Revision at Duke University, 1856-1976, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Michelle Chen
    - "Personal Space: On Sexual Identity, Sexual Violence, and Intersectionality" (zine). Gender, Sexuality, and Feminist Studies 290, 2016 (Box 1)
  - Kristin Love Collister
    - The Struggle Between the Students and the Faculty over the Tenure Policy at Duke University, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Erin Cooperrider
    - From Conception to Construction: Building the Duke Chapel, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Deborah K. Doolittle
    - The Social Experiment of Camp William James, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Laura Hotchkiss
    - Trinity Park: the Development of a Neighborhood... 1977 (Box 1)
  - Michael J. Jacobs
    - The 1942 Rose Bowl: A Story of War Adjustment and Southern Pride, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Richard A. "Tony" Jenkins
    - A Preliminary Examination of the Relationship between North Carolina Methodism and Trinity College at the Time of its Removal to Durham, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Deborah Kendall papers A83-105
    - Framing the Takeover: How local newspapers reported the February, 1969 racial demonstrations at Duke University, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous clippings from Durham Morning-Herald; Raleigh News and Observer; Charlotte Observer; Greensboro Daily News; and Washington Post regarding the 1969 Allen Building Takeover (Box 1)
  - Linda K. Kerber
    - 'Why Should Girls Be Learn'd and Wise?' The Unfinished Work of Alice Mary Baldwin, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Jeff Kessler
    - Duke's Field of Dreams [Jake Coombs Field], 1998 (Box 1)
  - Robert Kroll
    - Daring to Doubt the Myth: Conceptions of America in 1940 and the Boys of Camp William James, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Greg Lundberg papers
    - Black Power and the Allen Building Takeover: A Culmination of Issues, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Charles McLarty
    - Duke Chapel: A Study of its Origins, Antecedents, and Architectural Role on Campus, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Shandiin Herrera
    Scope and Contents
    Herrera's paper was the winner of the 2017 Multimedia Essay Contest held by The Other, a Duke blog focused on identity and social justice.
    - "A Forgotten Pride: Navajo Identity", 2017 (Box 1)
      Published online April 17, 2017.
  - Jean O'Barr
    - Gender at Duke Class, Fall 2006 (2 folders) (Box 2)
  - William E. Pike
    - A Modern Model for the United Methodist University: The History of the Connection between Duke University and the Methodist Tradition, 2003 (Box 2)
  - David A. Skidmore, Jr.
    - Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man: Reynolds Price, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Damian Stamer
    - Durham's First Pizza Pie: A History of Annamarias, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Chandler C. Smith
    - Desegregation and the Admissions Policies at Duke University, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Henry Mark Stichel
    - 'Stirring up the fires of race antipathy:' the summary of the John Spencer Bassett's early writing and thought, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Emily Thompson, Palmer Prize
    - Montaigne: Est-il Sceptique? (Box 2)
  - Susan L. Valente
    - The Mason Crum Papers: Hope for a Desegregated America? 1987 (Box 2)
  - Leah Wise
    - Stirring the Pot: Oliver Harvey's Narrative Account of the Struggle to Organize Duke University, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Social Thought in Ten Elizabeth Dramatists, Essays by Graduate Students at Duke University, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Investigation of High-Velocity Sliding Contact between a Rocket Sled and a Rail, Senior Project of Paul Follansbee, 1972 Spring (Box 2)